lpl.com 2008-05-09

# LPL Financial: Privacy Policy

LPL Financial (“LPL”) and its family of affiliated companies are committed to maintaining the trust and confidence of our customers. We want you to understand how we protect your privacy when we collect and use personal information in the course of business, as well as the measures we take to safeguard your information. Keeping customer information secure and private is a priority at LPL.

Please take a moment to review our Privacy Policy and contact us with any questions you may have. Thank you for the trust you have placed in us. We look forward to continuing to serve your needs.

While providing service to you, we collect non–public personal information from the following sources: 

  * Account applications and other standard forms — i.e., name, address, Social Security number, assets, types and amounts of investments, transactions and income.  

  * LPL transactions and affiliate companies including those that work closely with us to provide you with diverse financial products and services - i.e., your account balance, payment history, parties to transactions, types and amounts of investments, transactions and credit card usage.   

  * Consumer reporting agencies — i.e., your credit worthiness and credit history.  

  * Information obtained when verifying applications or other forms - this may be obtained from your current or past employers, or from other institutions where you conduct financial transactions.

Keeping your information secure is one of our most important responsibilities. We restrict access to your non–public personal information to those employees and agents who are providing products or services to you. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards that comply with federal standards to guard your non–public personal information.

We may occasionally use a "cookie" in order to provide better service to you, to facilitate your use of our website, to track usage of the website and to address security hazards. (A cookie is a small piece of information that a website stores on a personal computer and can be retrieved later.) We may use cookies for administrative purposes, such as to store your preference for certain kinds of information. None will contain information that will enable anyone to contact you via telephone, email or any other means. If you are uncomfortable with the use of the cookie technology, you can set your browsers to decline cookies. However, you may be unable to utilize certain features of our website if you refuse cookies.

We do not sell, share or disclose your non–public personal information to non–affiliated third–party marketing companies. We may disclose all of the information we collect, as described above in the "Collecting Non–public Personal Information" section to companies that perform marketing or other services on our behalf, or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements.

All of these companies are contractually obligated to keep the information that we provide confidential and use the information only for the services required and as allowed by applicable law or regulation, and are not permitted to share or use the information for any other purpose. We may disclose non–public personal information about you in connection with the transfer of your account to another financial institution at your request or the request of your representative. If you do not want LPL to disclose your non–public personal information with your advisor's new financial institution, please contact us as directed below.

We may also disclose non–public personal information as permitted or required by law. These disclosures typically include information to process transactions on your behalf, to conduct our operations, to follow your instructions as you authorize, or to protect the security of our financial records.

We are permitted by law to share within our family of affiliated companies, information about our transactions or experiences with you, such as account balance or payment history.

If you decide to close your account(s) or become an inactive customer, we will adhere to the privacy policies and practices as described in this notice. We reserve the right to change this policy at any time and you will be notified if changes occur.

Since LPL offers a variety of financial products and services, you may receive more than one privacy notice from us. 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, contact us by writing to: 

Privacy Management, c/o Legal Department   
LPL Financial   
One Beacon Street, 22nd Floor   
Boston, MA 02108

Click here to download the opt out form.

_This Privacy Policy applies to consumers who are customers or former customers of the LPL Financial family of affiliated companies in the United States. The LPL Financial family of affiliated companies are LPL Financial, its subsidiaries and certain affiliates, including Independent Advisers Group Corporation, The Private Trust Company, N.A., Innovex Mortgage, Inc. and LPL Insurance Associates, Inc._
